

# Pablo González

COMPUTER ENGINEER · PYTHON ENGINEER

Salamanca, Castilla y León, Spain

□ 689182380 | ☑ gonzrubio.pablo@gmail.com | 🏕 www.nonuser.es | 🖸 n0nuser | 🛅 nonuser

## Summary.

Hey there! I'm Pablo González, a Computer Engineer with a specialization in backend engineering and web-services development. My expertise lies in Python, particularly using Django or FastAPI. I'm a GNU/Linux user, a big advocate of Open Source Software, and passionate about improving code readability and functionality. When I'm not coding, I enjoy tending to my plants, playing sports, and helping others.

### Education

#### **USAL(University of Salamanca)**

Salamanca, Spain

B.S. IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Sep. 2018 - Jul. 2022

 Got a 10 with Honours in the Final Degree Project: Prometheus-like system for monitoring and command execution on multiple devices from different networks.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**Axpe Consulting S.L.** 

Salamanca, Spain

PYTHON ENGINEER - FULL TIME

Dec. 2022 - Present

- Full-Stack Developer with strong backend skills, skilled in refactoring and optimizing Python scripts, enhancing system performance using MongoDB or PostgreSQL, and leading backend development projects.
- · Proficient in designing and implementing API-first systems using FastAPI, SQLAlchemy 2.0, and Git with Github.
- Demonstrated success in implementing new backends using FastAPI and optimizing existing applications for improved efficiency, as well as deploying systems using Docker.
- Passionate about improving code readability, maintainability, and backend functionality.

#### Panelais Producciones S.A.

Huerta del Tormes. Salamanca.

Spain

PYTHON ENGINEER & SYSADMIN - FULL TIME

Mar. 2022 - Dec. 202.

- Design and development of a web application based on Django with integration of multiple Microsoft SQL Server databases, which allows the internal management of Panelais, and the visualization of data in real time from the machines and continuous production lines.
- · Analysis and improvement of SQL queries.
- Administration of Linux servers for the maintenance of data extraction services with MQTT, the deployment of the different web pages and the monitoring of the databases through scripting in Python.

#### Sidisel Electrónica S.L.

Villamayor, Salamanca, Spain

Jan. 2022 - Feb. 2022

Python Developer - Internship Contract

- Gitlab for version control and incident management.
- Docker for microservice deployment and management.
- Pytest and Tox for functional testing of servers' API.
- Django integration with services like Wagtail.
- Python client interaction with microservices.
- Python/Django based microservices for transactions and basic information management.

#### **Ecoinnotec S.L.**

Carbajosa de la Sagrada, Salamanca, Spain

Jul. 2021 - Sep. 2021

SYSADMIN - INTERNSHIP CONTRACT

- Design and implementation of an API RESTful monitoring solution for Windows and Linux based on Python/Flask.
- Script Development for Odoo ERP server deployment.
- IT Helpdesk.
- PC preparing for new workers.
- · General IT troubleshooting.

APRIL 4, 2023 PABLO GONZÁLEZ · RESUME



#### **Final Degree Project - Monitor**

Salamanca, Spain

University of Salamanca Jun. 2021 - Jul. 2022

- A FastAPI based agent capable of command execution, deployed on hosts that require monitoring.
- The agent sends requests to a Django/Django REST Framework web app that manages data and presents it.
- The web app is deployed with Nginx and Uvicorn for the Web Server, Redis for the background tasks and PostgreSQL for the database.
- Deployment of the web app is done with **Docker**.
- Final Grade: 10 with Honours.

### **Honors & Awards**

#### NATIONAL

Dec. 2020 Semifinalist, II National CyberLeague Nov. 2019 17th finalist, I National Cyberleague Sep. 2019 Participant, 1st Regional Cybersecurity Forum

Oct. 2018 1st Classified, I National Cyberleague at USAL

Online Madrid, Spain

Salamanca, Spain

Salamanca, Spain

# Writing\_

**Personal Blog** www.nonuser.es

FOUNDER & WRITER Oct. 2019 - Present

• Write IT posts about programming, administration of Linux services and Hack The Box machine resolutions.